<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting started on SiriDB documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting started on SiriDB documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>For Ubuntu we have a deb package available which can be downloaded here.
Note: SiriDB requires libexpat1, libuv1, libpcre2-8-0 and libcleri0 these libraries can be easily installed using apt:
apt install libexpat1 libuv1 libpcre2-8-0 libcleri0  Library libcleri0 is available from Ubuntu 18.04, for older versions a deb package can be found here: https://github.com/transceptor-technology/libcleri/releases/latest
 The .deb package installs a configuration file at /etc/siridb/siridb.conf. You might want to view or change this file before starting SiriDB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build from source</title>
      <link>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/build_from_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/build_from_source/</guid>
      <description>From version 2.0.19 libcleri is not included as part of this source anymore and needs to be installed separately. libcleri can be found here: https://github.com/transceptor-technology/libcleri or can be installed using apt.
 Linux Install the following requirements: (Ubuntu 18.04)
sudo apt install libcleri-dev sudo apt install libpcre2-dev sudo apt install libuv1-dev sudo apt install libyajl-dev sudo apt install uuid-dev Compile (replace Release with Debug for a debug build):
cd .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/configuration/</guid>
      <description>SiriDB can start with environment variables and/or with a configuration file. By default SiriDB will search for the configuration file in /etc/siridb/siridb.conf but alternatively you can specify a custom path by using the -c/--config argument.
$ siridb-server -c /my/path/siridb.conf An example configuration file can be found here: https://github.com/SiriDB/siridb-server/blob/master/siridb.conf
However be aware that the environment variables will overwrite the configuration file settings if both apply to the same setting.
Environmental variables:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start up server</title>
      <link>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/start_up_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.siridb.net/getting_started/start_up_server/</guid>
      <description>Now that SiriDB is installed and configured, you can start a SiriDB server:
$ siridb-server If you use a configuration file instead of the environment variables and this file is stored at a different location than the default /etc/siridb/siridb.conf; you have to specify the path using the -c/--config argument:
$ siridb-server -c /my/path/siridb.conf Flag information    Flag Description     -h, --help Show the help message and exit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>